<?xml version="1.0"?>
<course>

	<unit title="Unit 1: the Web &amp; HTML5 &amp; CSS3">
		<lesson title="the Web">
			<content>

				<list>
					The World Wide Web, shortened to the Web, is a system of interlinked, hypertext documents accessed
					via the Internet. It is created to share files/documents and overcome the barrier of different file formats.
				</list>
				<list>
					Hypertext refers to text on a computer that will lead the user to other, related information on demand.
					hypertext documents are created using a special kind of document formatting or "markup" language called
					HyperText Markup Language (HTML).
				</list>
				<list>
					HTML is sent or received over the network using HyperText Transfer Protocol (HTTP). A browser is a software
					program which interprets the HTML documents and displays it on the user’s screen.
				</list>
				<list>
					A web server is server software, or hardware dedicated to running said software, that can satisfy World Wide Web
					client requests. A web server can, in general, contain one or more websites. A web server processes incoming network
					requests over HTTP and several other related protocols.
				</list>
				<list>
					The HTTP protocol is a request/response protocol based on the client/server based architecture where web browsers,
					robots and search engines, etc. act like HTTP clients, and the Web server acts as a server.
				</list>
				<list>
					The HTTP client sends a request to the server in the form of a request method, URI, and protocol version,
					followed by a MIME-like message containing request modifiers, client information, and possible body content over
					a TCP/IP connection.
					The HTTP server responds with a status line, including the message's protocol version and a success or error code,
					followed by a MIME-like message containing server information, entity meta information, and possible
					entity-body content.
				</list>
				<list>
					Each document/resource on the WWW needs to have an identifier in order to be accessed by others. A Uniform
					Resource Identifier (URI), is a compact string of characters used to identify or name a resource. A Uniform Resource
					Locator (URL) is a URI which provides means of obtaining the resource by describing its network "location".
				</list>
			</content>
		</lesson>

		<lesson title="HTML5">
			<content>
				<list>
					HTML5 is the latest evolution of the standard that defines HTML. The term represents two different concepts.
					It is a new version of the language HTML, with new elements, attributes, and behaviors, and a larger set of
					technologies that allows the building of more diverse and powerful Web sites and applications.
				</list>
				<list>
					Text Level Semantics:
					
						<def>a element</def> -- anchor. useful to provide a link for a block of content. also helpful for cross
						reference using id.
						<def>em element</def> -- emphasis. emphasizing a particular word or phrase.
						<def>i element</def> -- change of context. voice, thinking, mood, etc.
						<def>strong element</def> -- represents strong importance of its contents, does not change the meaning.
						<def>b</def> -- content to draw attention. without adding importance or change in mood or voice.
						<def>mark</def> -- part of text highlighted for reference purpose. may not be intended by original author.
						<def>small element</def> -- small print. disclaimers, caveats, legal restrictions or copyrights.
						Meant for short runs of text only. It doesn't mean low importance.
						<def>s element</def> -- content no longer relevant or accurate. not to be confused with del
						<def>data</def> -- provides machine readable form of content.
						<def>time</def> -- special case of data. date, time, time zone, etc.
						<def>
							and much more
							<span>&#8942;</span>
						</def>
					
				</list>
				<list>
					Sections:
					
						<def>body</def> -- main content of the document. just one per page.
						<def>section</def> -- parts of the document. e.g. home page can be split into intro, news, contact, etc.
						<def>article</def> -- useful for syndication. independently distributable or reusable.
						<def>nav</def> -- navigation. a section with navigation links. special case of section.
						<def>aside</def> -- content related to and part of main content. could contain q quote.
						<def>h1, h2, ..., h6</def> -- headings, subheadings
						<def>hgroup</def> -- heading of a section. used for grouping h1, h2, ....
						<def>header</def> -- group of introductory or navigation aids. could contain hgroup
						<def>footer</def> -- represents footer. not necessarily that has to appear in the end.
						because it is presentation concern. e.g. author, copyright, etc.
						<def>address</def> -- not meant for postal addresses unless it is related to contact
						info of the current page or article.
					
				</list>
				<list>
					Lists:
					
						<def>ol</def> -- each list item can be created with the li tag. Could manually change the numbers
						appear on the list items. The type of numeral can be changed by type attribute.
						<def>ul</def> --  each list item can be created with the li tag. can nest lists to represent sub-items.
						The nested list has to be a child of the li element.
						<def>dl</def> --  consists of name-value groups, where the name is given in the dt element,
						and the value is given in the dd element.
					
				</list>
				<list>
					Input Control Elements:
					
						<def>type</def> -- Identifies the type of input control to display. Acceptable values are hidden, text,
						tel, url, email, password, date, time, number, range, color, checkbox, radio, file,
						submit, image, reset, and button. Defaults to text.
						<def>checked</def> -- Has type attribute radio and checkbox, boolean attribute indicates the control
						is selected or not.
						<def>multiple</def> -- Allow the user to pass more than one file or email type input.
						<def>required</def> -- Indicates a value must be present or the element must be checked in order for the
						form to be submitted.
						<def>autofocus</def> -- The input element should get the focus when page loads.
					

				</list>
				<list>
					IFrames:
					
						<def>name</def> -- Sets the element's name, to be used with an a tag to change the iframe's src.
						<def>src</def> -- Specifies the page that will be displayed in the frame.
						<def>srcdoc</def> -- Specifies the content that will be displayed in the frame. The content must be
						valid HTML.
						<def>sandbox</def> -- When set, the contents of the iframe is treated as being from a unique origin
						and features including scripts, plugins, forms and popups will be disabled.
						Restrictions can be selectively relaxed by adding a space separated list of values.
						See the table in Remarks for possible values.
					

				</list>
				<list>
					Event Attributes:
					
						<def>onblur</def> -- Fires the moment that the element loses focus.
						<def>onchange</def> -- Fires the moment when the value of the element is changed.
						<def>oncontextmenu</def> -- Script to be run when a context menu is triggered.
						<def>onfocus</def> -- Fires the moment when the element gets focus.
						<def>oninput</def> -- Script to be run when an element gets user input.
						<def>oninvalid</def> -- Script to be run when an element is invalid.
						<def>onreset</def> -- Fires when the Reset button in a form is clicked.
						<def>onsearch</def> -- Fires when the user writes something in a search field (for input ="search").
						<def>onselect</def> -- Fires after some text has been selected in an element.
						<def>onsubmit</def> -- Fires when a form is submitted.
						<def>onkeydown</def> -- Fires when a user is pressing a key.
						<def>onkeypress</def> -- Fires when a user presses a key.
						<def>onkeyup</def> -- Fires when a user releases a key.
					
				</list>
			</content>
		</lesson>

		<lesson title="CSS3">
			<content>
				<list>
					<strong>CSS selectors</strong> -- Ways to identify the portion of html to set the styles to. It could be based on id, class, span, div, etc.
				</list>
				<list>
					<strong>Precedence</strong> -- The styles will be applied on a particular precedence. User's browser preferences take the top priority. Then the parent element's style, and so on.
				</list>
				<list>
					<strong>Possibilities</strong> -- font size, typeface, underline, overline, strikethrough, color, etc.
				</list>
				<list>
					<strong>bullet styles</strong> can change. Within the bullet points first can be different, or the last can be different, or the nth item can be different.
				</list>
				<list>
					Text:
					
						<def>text-shadow</def> -- provides shadow effect.
						<def>text-transform</def> -- uppercase, camel case, etc.
					
				</list>
				<list>
					Font:
					
						<def>font-size</def> -- don't use pt or px since they cannot be standardized. Reference this article
						for best practice.
						<def>font possibilities</def> -- simply everything. font-weight, line-height, letter-spacing,
						word-spacing, font-variant, font-style, alignments, indent, white-space,
						text-decoration
					
				</list>
				<list>
					color and background:
					
						<def>ways to specify colors</def> -- named colors, hex, rgb, hsl, rgba, hsla
						<def>background</def> -- color, image, pattern / tiling, positioning, attachment (scroll/fixed).
						Allows shorthand for mixing different options.
					
				</list>
				<list>
					List:
						<def>list-style-type</def> -- none for horizontal menu. numbered, roman, circle, etc.
						<def>list-style-image</def> -- image in place of bullets
						<def>list-style-position</def> -- level of indentation
				</list>
				<list>
					Table:
						<def>border, border-spacing, caption-side</def>
						There are just too many ways to slice and dice tables. Sky is the limit!
						border styles, background color for specific row/column/cell, etc.
				</list>
				<list>
					Box:<br></br>
					
						As opposed to inline elements such as <def>i, em,</def> etc., special styling can be done for block style
						or box elements such as <def>div</def>.
						Background colour, margin, alignment, border, outline, stacking, overflow are some of
						the possibilities.
						<def>cursor</def> allows to set a cursor style when a particular element is hovered over.
						<def>border-radius</def> provides fillets for box. Specific fillet is also possible such
						as border-bottom-right-border.
					
				</list>
				<list>Get rid of the underline in links: text-decoration: none</list>
			</content>
		</lesson>

		<quiz title="Unit 1 Quiz">
			<question txt="1. Which value of Socket.readyState atribute of WebSocket indicates that the connection is going through the closing handshake?">
				<ans correct="0">0</ans>
				<ans correct="0">1</ans>
				<ans correct="1"><label>2</label></ans>
				<ans correct="0">3</ans>
			</question>
			<question txt="2. Which of the following tag can be used to mark up a conversation in HTML5?">
				<ans correct="1"><label>dialog</label></ans>
				<ans correct="0">nav</ans>
				<ans correct="0">footer</ans>
				<ans correct="0">figure</ans>
			</question>
			<question txt="3. Which built-in method adds one or more elements to the end of an array and returns the new length of the array?">
				<ans correct="1"><label>push()</label></ans>
				<ans correct="0">last()</ans>
				<ans correct="0">put()</ans>
				<ans correct="0">None of the above</ans>
			</question>
			<question txt="4. What is css Float?">
				<ans correct="0">allows other elements to wrap around an element</ans>
				<ans correct="0">element can be pushed to the left or right</ans>
				<ans correct="0">element can be pushed to any direction</ans>
				<ans correct="1"><label>both a and b above</label></ans>
			</question>
      <question txt="5. Which of the following defines a measurement relative to a font's x-height?">
        <ans correct="0">%</ans>
        <ans correct="0">cm</ans>
        <ans correct="0">em</ans>
        <ans correct="1"><label>ex</label></ans>
      </question>
		</quiz>

	</unit>



</course>